Guide to the Oral History of the American Left: Radical Histories Collection OH 002
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Oral History of the American Left: Radical Histories
1920-1980
OH 002
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
20.0 linear feet Approximately 390 cassettes
The Tamiment Library at New York University established the Oral History of the American Left in 1976 in order to collect and preserve the memories of veteran activists. These interviews describe seven decades of Left politics from the 1910s through the 1970s. They document the full spectrum of left politics in the twentieth century: Socialism, Communism, Anarchism, Trotskyism, and the New Left. There are interviews with both leaders and rank-and-file activists.
Tamiment Library.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions when release forms are indicated.
Historical/Biographical Note
New York University’s Tamiment Library established the Oral History of the American Left (OHAL) in 1976. The purpose of this project was to expand the archive of American labor and radicalism through the creation of “living documents,” the memories of veteran activists. The idea was “to create an archive of recorded reminiscences by participants in trade union struggles, political organizations, and grass-roots political and cultural activity.” Paul Buhle was the Director of the project. Roger Keeran was Co-Director in the early years. Jon Bloom joined the project in 1977 and worked as an interviewer, coordinator, and fundraiser.
The project began with several years of varied interviewing supported by small grants from the Rabinowitz and Bronson Cutting Foundations. The New Jersey Historical Commission provided funding in 1978 to support a series of interviews on radicalism in New Jersey, during the 1930-1960 period. Later, Ruth F. Prago developed the idea for a radio series based on interviews to be conducted for the OHAL collection, and together with Pacifica Radio the project received a one-year grant from the New York State Council for the Humanities to conduct interviews with twenty-five women about radicalism during the1930s. OHAL received major funding in 1982-1983 from the National Endowment for the Humanities. With this support, Paul Buhle conducted a sweeping oral history of ethnic-immigrant radicalism, its press and fraternal organizations. The NEH grant also enabled OHAL to collect hundreds of hours of interviews made by filmmakers on American anarchism, the Hollywood blacklist, the Communist Party, the Columbia University student strike of 1968, and other subjects.
The project also produced seven issues of a newsletter, and the transcript of a two-day conference co-sponsored by OHAL and the Tamiment Library on the occasion of the opening of the Max Shactman Papers.
Scope and Content Note
The tapes and transcript in the Oral History of the American Left collection came from a variety of sources. Most of the interviews were done by Jon Bloom, Paul Buhle, Bea Lemisch, and Ruth Prago. They cover many subjects including: immigrant/ethnic radicalism, labor, women's history, radical newspapers, fraternal organizations, and student radicalism from 1910s through 1970s. The earliest interviews were done with those men and women who could recall the 1910s -1920s. The effect of the Russian Revolution on the Left in the United States, the formation of social and cultural institutions by the "New Immigrant" groups of all Left political shadings, the history of Socialism and Anarchism, and the troubled early years of American Communism. A particular effort was made to interview rank-and-file or middle-level leadership activists. These women and men for the most part did not leave written records behind so their oral histories are the only historical record that is available. A number of these interviews focused on "radical women." Many interviews focus on the labor movement, particularly the needle trades unions and the early years of the Congress of Industrial Organizations.
The immigrant-ethnic interviews might be the most unique element of the collection. OHAL interviewed representative figures from the Jewish, Finnish, Slovenia, Greek, Hungarian, Polish, Italian, Ukrainian, Lithuanian, Japanese, Scandinavian, and Spanish Left. A handful of tapes recall the African American experience.
Several interviews are with participants in the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, who fought in the Spanish Civil War, as the U.S. component of the International Brigades, and several other interviews document related activities. Several interviews document the long tenure of Jasper McLevy, Socialist Party mayor of Bridgeport, Connecticut, 1933-1957.
Ninety-five percent of these interviews are on cassette tapes with accompanying indexes. The rest are transcripts without tapes. Thanks to Information about format is noted in the inventory.
Notable interviewees include: Notable individuals interviewed include: Herbert Aptheker, Rosalyn Fraad Baxandall, Daniel Berrigan, Abner Berry, James Boggs, George Breitman, Rose Chernin, Malcolm Cowley, Samuel Darcy, Solon De Leon, Hal Draper, Raya Dunayevskaya, Melech Epstein, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Hugo Gellert, Todd Gitlin, Martine Glaberman, Albert Glotzer, Itshe Goldberg, Louis Harap, Michael Harrington, Howard "Stretch" Johnson, Mary Kolehmainen, Meridel Le Sueur, A.B. Magil, Thomas McGrath, Ernest Rice McKinney, Clarence Norris, Paul Novik, Harvey O'Connor, Louise Patterson, George Rawick, Lester Rodney, Annette Rubinstein, Pete Seeger, Norman Thomas, Stan Weir, Myra Tanner Weiss.
Several group interviews or conferences were recorded pertaining to the following organizations: Catholic Worker Movement, International Labor Defense, Johnson-Forest Tendency, Matteotti Club, Medem Jewish Socialist Group, Socialist Party(U.S.), Southern Negro Youth Congress, Workers Party (1940-1949), Workers Party (1940-1949).
Arrangement
Alphabetical by name.
The files are grouped into 1 series:
Container list
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born.; Baxandall, Rosalyn Fraad, 1939- --Interviews.; Berrigan, Daniel--Interviews.; Berry, Abner--Interviews.; Bloom, Jonathan.; Boggs, James--Interviews.; Breitman, George -- |v Interviews; Buhle, Paul, 1944-; Chernin, Rose--Interviews.; Communist Party of the United States of America--Interviews..; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898- --Interviews.; Darcy, Samuel, 1905-; De Leon, Solon, 1883-; Draper, Hal--Interviews.; Dunayevskaya, Raya--Interviews.; Epstein, Melech--Interviews.; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence--Interviews.; Foner, Henry--Interviews.; Foner, Moe, 1915- --Interviews.; Gellert, Hugo, 1892-1985--Interviews.; Gitlin, Todd--Interviews.; Glaberman, Martin--Interviews.; Glotzer, Albert, 1908-1999. -- |v Interviews; Goldberg, Itshe--Interviews.; Harap, Louis--Interviews.; Harrington, Michael, 1928- --Interviews.; Industrial Workers of the World--Interviews.; International Labor Defense--Interviews.; James, C. L. R., (Cyril Lionel Robert), 1901-1989. -- |v Interviews; Johnson, Howard, 1915- --Interviews.; Johnson-Forest Tendency--Interviews.; Kolehmainen, Mary--Interviews.; Le Sueur, Meridel--Interviews.; Lemisch, Bea.; Magil, A. B. --Interviews.; Matteotti Club--Interviews.; McGrath, Thomas, 1916-1990--Interviews.; McKinney, Ernest Rice, 1886-1984--Interviews.; McLevy, Jasper--Interviews.; Nelson, Steve, 1903- --Interviews.; Novick, P., 1891- --Interviews.; O'Connor, Harvey, 1897-1987--Interviews.; Patterson, Louise Thompson, 1901-1999--Interviews.; Prago, Ruth.; Rawick, George P., 1929- --Interviews.; Rodney, Lester, 1911- --Interviews.; Rubinstein, Annette T. (Annette Teta), 1910-2007--Interviews.; Seeger, Pete, 1919-; Socialist Party (U.S.)--Interviews.; Socialist Workers Party--Interviews.; Southern Negro Youth Congress--Interviews.; Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.)--Interviews.; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968--Interviews.; Trade Union Unity League (U.S.).; Weir, Stan--Interviews.; Weiss, Myra Tanner--Interviews.; Workers Party (1940-1949)--Interviews.; Workmen's Circle/Arbeiter Ring--Interviews.; Young Communist League of the U.S.; African American radicals |v Interviews.; Anarchism |z United States.; Anarchists |z United States |v Interviews.; Communism |z United States.; Communists--United States--Interviews.; Emigration and immigration--United States--Interviews.; Finnish American radicals--Interviews.; Hungarian American radicals--Interviews.; Italian American radicals--Interviews.; Jewish radicals--United States--Interviews.; Labor union members--United States--Interviews.; Labor unions |z United States.; Labor |z United States.; Oral histories (document genre); Right and left (Political science).; Slavic American radicals--Interviews.; Socialism |z United States.; Socialism--Bridgeport (Conn.); Socialists--United States--Interviews.; Spain--History--Civil War, 1936-1939--Participation, American--Interviews.; Student movements--United States--Interviews.; Trotskyists--United States--Interviews.; Women employees--United States--Interviews.; Women radicals--United States--Interviews.
- Minka Alesh Description:Slovenian Benefit Society and socialist party, Haberdashery Union, New York and Chicago, c. 1910-1920s, Oct 26, 1982 (Cassette 1, Cd ohaloh020146p1 / /ohaloh020146p2)
  General note
  Index available
- Ben Alexrod, Oct 4, 1979 (Cassette 391)
  General Note
  no access cassette / master only
- Jose Alvarez Description: Communist movement in Ybor City, Florida, tobacco factories and unions; 1920-40s; Fidel Castro; 1950s., Mar 15, 1983 (Cassette 2, Cd ohaloh020147b1p1 / ohaloh020147b1p2, Cd ohaloh020148b1p3)
  Transcript, Box 1 and index available
- Freda Hogan Ameringer, Dec 22, 1977 (Cassette 362, Cd ohaloh020153p1 / ohaloh020153p2)
  no access cassettes available / master only
- Freda Hogan Ameringer (Cassette 362, Cd ohaloh020154p1 / ohaloh020154p2)
- Freda Hogan Ameringer (Cd ohaloh020155b1p1 / ohaloh020155b1p2, Cd ohaloh020156b1p3)
- Vicky Amter Description: Communist Party, lower east side, N.Y., Local 65 shop steward; reactions to emergence of the New Left. c. 1940s-1960s, Feb 19, 1978 (Cd ohaloh020149p1 / ohaloh020149p2, Cassette 3)
  no tape
- Herbert Aptheker Description: College radicalism in 1930s; Communist Party, 1976 (Cassette No Tapes)
  Transcript available, Box 1
- Harry Aronek Description: Immigration; political and cultural activities in New York Jewish community, 1930s-1950s., Oct 25, 1978 (Cassette 4, Cd ohaloh020150b1p1 / ohaloh020150b1p2, Cd ohaloh020151b1p3)
- Jacob Aspitz Description: Los Angeles, Jewish Left and Communism; Yiddishe Kultur Farband., Apr 8, 1970 (Cd ohaloh020157b1p1 / ohaloh020157b1p2, Cd ohaloh020158b1p3 / ohaloh020158b1p4, Cassette 6)
- Sam Ashare (Cassette 5, Cd ohaloh020152p1 / ohaloh020152p2)
- Stanley Banach Description: Army life in Vietnam and Germany; union activity at Electric Boat/Quonset Point, union activity at Brown and Sharpe c. 1950-1982, Apr 11, 1984 (Cd ohaloh0200089b1p1 / ohaloh0200089b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200090b1p3 / ohaloh0200090b1p4, Cassette 7)
- Eugene Barnett Description: Industrial Workers of the World, lumberwork; West Virginia coal miners, repression in Centralia, PA. c. 1910a, Early 1940s (Cassette Transcript only)
- Walter Barry Description Trade Union Unity League and United Electrical Workers District 4, Westinghouse Elevator plant, c. 1930s-50s., Oct 12, 1980-Feb 4, 1980 (Cd ohaloh020159b1p1 / ohaloh020159b1p2, Cd ohaloh020160b1p3 / ohaloh020160b1p4, Cd ohaloh020161b1p5, Cassette 9)
  tape#: 3 U2A
- Irving Barshop, Oct. 12, 1973 (Cassette 334)
- Rosalyn Baxandall Description: political and cultural experiences in Madison, beginnings of Madison's women's movement. c. 1958, Nov 8, 1983 (Cassette 10)
- Bertha Bazell Description: Workman's Circle; Communist Party, 1930s-50s; harassment by the F.B.I. in the 1950s., Mar 10, 1981 (Cassette 11, Cd ohaloh020162p1 / ohaloh020162p2)
- Ray Bell Description: Socialism/communism, Spain in WWII, Aug 2, 1985 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Fay Bennett Description: College anti-war movement; American Student Union; Keep America Out of War Congress; postwar work with National Sharecroppers' Fund. c. 1930s-1940s, May 26, 1983 (Cassette 12, Cd ohaloh020163b1p1 / ohaloh020163b1p2, Cd ohaloh020164b1p3 / ohaloh020164b1p4)
- Herman Benson
- Jack Bergen Description: Bridgeport in 1910s; Depression and Jasper McLevy; SP in Connecticut state politics, 1930s., 1967 (Item Transcript only)
  Transcript available, Box 1no tape
- John T. Bernard Description: Mesaba Park Coop.,tribute to John Bernard, U.S. representative 1936-38; speeches by former Minnesota Governor Elmer Benson et al. about Bernard's record in Congress; response from Bernard., Jun 25, 1977 (Cassette 14, Cd ohaloh020165b1p1 / ohaloh020165b1p2, Cd ohaloh020166b1p3 / ohaloh020166b1p4, Cd ohaloh020167b1p5 / ohaloh020167b1p6)
- Daniel Berrigan Description activities during the 1960s, Catonsville incident., Apr 1, 1970 (Cassette 15A-C)
- Abner Berry and Mark Naison Description: Communist Party in Harlem, 1930s; Ethiopia Defense Committee; Unemployed Councils., 1974-1977 (Cd ohal02000b1p1 to ohaloh020002b1p4, Cd ohaloh020003p1 and ohaloh020003p2, Cd ohaloh020004p1 and ohal020004p2, Cassette 16, Cd ohaloh020005b1p1 to ohaloh020006b1p4, Cd Access - OH-02-001 to OH-02-006)
- Steve Beumer Description Socialist Workers Party; experiences as bus driver and union activist in Detroit, c. 1960s- 1970s., Jun 21, 1975 (Cassette 17, Cd ohaloh020168b1p1 / ohaloh020168b1p2, Cd ohaloh020169b1p3 / ohaloh020169b1p4, Cd ohaloh020170b1p5 / ohaloh020170b1p6)
- Martin Birnbaum Description: New Yorker Volkszeitung, Moshe Nadir; Yiddish literary community, Proletpen; c. 1920s., 1978 (Cassette 18, Cd ohaloh020171b1p1 / ohaloh020171b1p2, Cd ohaloh020172b1p3 / ohaloh020172b1p4)
- Martin Birnbaum, Feb 5, 1978 (Cassette 18, Cd ohaloh020173p1 / ohaloh020173p2)
- Martin Birnbaum Description: Yiddish literary work; Moshe Nadir; Jewish popular culture., 1983 (Cassette 19, Cd ohaloh020174p1 / ohaloh020174p2)
- Fred Blair Description: Left from Polish sector, Meta Berger in Wisconsin Party and Blair's leadership; communism in Wisconsin: c. 1930s-1950s., Jul 26, 1983 (Cd access OH-02-007, Cassette 20, Cd ohaloh020007p1 / ohaloh020007p2)
  Transcript available,Box 1
- Norman Bloomfield Description: Young People's Socialist League, 1930s; Trotskyism; Berkeley campus; work in shipyards., May 7, 1983 (Cassette 21, Cd ohaloh020175p1 / ohaloh020175p2)
- Grace Lee Boggs Description: radical politics in New York, late 1930s; Workers Party and Johnson-Forest tendency; c. 1930s-1950s, Mar 28, 1983 (Cassette 22, Cd Access OH-02-008, Cd ohaloh02008p1 / ohaloh020008p2)
- James Boggs Description: factory life in Detroit, 1930s-40s; Johnson-Forest Tendency; activities in 1960s-70s., Mar 29, 1983 (Cassette 23, Cd OH-02-009 / OH-02-010, Cd ohaloh020009b1p1 / ohaloh020009b1p2 / ohaloh020010b1p3)
- Paul Booth Description: Students for a Democratic Society, 1960s, Oct 1969 (Cassette Index only)
- Frank Bohn Description: Memories of Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Thomas Hagerty, the Catholic church, Socialist Labor Party, 3/1/1958 (Cd access OH-02-011, Cd ohaloh020011p1, Cassette 24)
- Fannie Borun Description: International Ladies Garment Workers Union; Soviet Union; women and the Communist Party; c. 1920s-1930s., Jan 6, 1981 (Cassette 25, Cd ohaloh020176p1 / ohaloh020176p1)
- Judy Boudon Description: Spanish immigrant community in New York, office and factory work; America Labor Party; Communist Party, 1930s., Feb 8, 1982 (Cassette 26, Cd Access OH-02-012 / OH-02-013, Cd ohaloh020012p1, Cd ohaloh020013p1 / ohaloh020013p2)
  Electronic transcript and Index available
- Thomas Brandon Description: Workers' Newsreel and Film and Photo League, early 1930s., Nov 4, 1976 (Cassette 27, Cd ohaloh020177p1 / ohaloh020177p2)
- Jeremy Brecher Description: Students for a Democratic Society, 1962-65, Mar 31, 1970 (Cassette 28)
  no access cassettes / Masters only
- George Breitman Description: Unemployed organizations in New Jersey; Socialist Workers Party, 1938-54., Jan 4, 1971 (Cassette 29, Cd Access OH-02-014 / OH-02-015 / OH-02-016, Cd ohaloh020014b1p1 / ohaloh020014b1p2, Cd ohaloh020015b1p3 / ohaloh020015b1p4, Cd ohaloh020016b1p5)
- Harry Brier Description: East End of London; anti- fascist activities, 1920-30s; Los Angeles and union activities, c. 1920s-1940s., Aug 26, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020017, Cd Aceess OH-02-017, Cassette 30)
- Miriam Braverman, Nov 8, 1984 (Cassette 364)
- Theodore Brise Description: Anarchism and Arbeter Ring, Los Angeles; Yiddish anarchist activists and the Rudolf Rocker Circle., Apr 18, 1980 (Cassette 31, Cd ohaloh020178p1 / ohaloh020178p2)
- Brookwood Labor College Description: Narration by Jon Bloom of slide show on history of Brookwood Labor College and Workers' Education Local 189, with comments by former Brookwood staff and students., Oct 10, 1982 (Cassette 32A-D)
- Niki Brorse n Description: Young Socialist Alliance, restaurant union, c. 1950-1970s., Oct 10, 1982 (Cassette 33, Cd ohaloh020179b1p1 / ohaloh020179b1p2, Cd ohaloh020180b1p3 / ohaloh020180b1p4)
- Peter Burch Description: Socialist Zionism, Socialist Workers Party and Young Socialist Alliance, Robert Williams case; c. 1950s-60s., Aug 24, 1976 (Cassette Transcript only)
  Transcript available, box 1
- David Burbank Description: Saint Louis radicalism, 1930s; Socialist Party, American Workers Party, Trotskyist movement, CLR James; gas workers' unionization., Oct 6, 1984 (Cassette 35, Cd ohaloh020181p1 / ohaloh020181p2)
- Ann Burlak Description: Rhode Island Labor activities, communism, early 1930s., 1977 (Cassette 35.1, Cd ohaloh020182b1p1 / ohaloh020182b1p2 / ohaloh020183b1p3 / ohaloh020183b1p4, Cd ohaloh020184b1p5 / ohaloh020184b1p6 /ohaloh020185b1p7 / ohaloh020185b1p8, Cd ohaloh020186b1p9 / ohaloh020186b1p10)
  no access cassettes / masters only
- Ann Burlak, n.d. (Cassette 36, Cd ohaloh020187p1)
- Violet Bjong, July 7, 1984 (Cassette 265, Cd ohaloh0200121p1 / ohaloh0200121p2)
- Fanny & Herman Cantor Description: Radicalism and cooperativism, 1920s-30s., Jan 11, 1979 (Cassette 37, Cd ohaloh020188p1 / ohaloh020188p2)
- Philip Caplowitz Description: Activities of Jewish Communists in unions; Yiddish Culture and Yiddishe Kultur Farband, 1930s-present., Nov 15, 1980 (Cassette 38, Cd ohaloh020189b1p1 / ohaloh020189b1p2, Cd ohaloh020190b1p3)
- Wendell Carroll Description: American Youth for Democracy; Independent Socialist League; ISL positions on Korean War, Rosenberg case, c. 1940s-1950s., Nov 30, 1983 (Cassette 39A-B)
  Transcript available
- Pincus Caruso Description: Origins of Labor (Poale) Zionism in Eastern Europe; Yiddishe Kempfer; Israel; c. 1930s-1940s., Mar 16, 1983 (Cassette 40A-B)
- Catholic Worker Conference Description: Program to honor Dorothy Day and founding of the Catholic Worker; panel comments by John Cort and others. Trinity College, Worcester, Massachusetts., May 2, 1983 (Cassette 41A-B)
- Bernard Chasanow Description: Narrative translation of part of his 1956 Yiddish autobiography, Days and Years., 1978 (Cd ohaloh0200091p1 / ohaloh0200091p2, Cassette 42)
- Bernard Chasanow Description: ILGWU, 1909-1928; Political activist in Russia, 1898-1909., May 31, 1978 (Cassette 43, Cd ohaloh020191b1p1 / ohaloh020191b1p2, Cd ohaloh020192b1p3 / ohaloh020192b1p4, Cd ohaloh020193b1p5 / ohaloh020193b1p6)
- Rev. Don Chase Description: US intervention in Nicaragua, 1928; Christian Socialism in San Francisco, 1930s-50s; Liberation Theology, 1970s-80s., Nov 5, 1983 (Cassette 44A-B)
- Rose Chernin Description: Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born, 1940s-1950s., Oct 25, 1983 (Cassette 45, Cd Access OH-02-018, Cd ohaloh020018p1 / ohaloh020018p2)
- Harold Christoffel Description: speaking of former president of United Auto Workers Local 248 (Allis Chalmers), 1930s., Jun 27, 1974 (Item Transcript only)
- Helen Ciminelli; Joe Richter; Ann David; Description: SNPJ (Slovenian Benefit Society) and Henry Wallace, 1930s - 1970s, Oct 6, 1983 (Cassette 47)
  tape#: 1 U2E
- Alice Citron Description: Teachers's Union; Teachers's Union; McCarthy era, 1930s-1940s., Jan 6, 1981 (Cd ohaloh020019p1 / ohaloh020019p2, Cd Access OH-02-019, Cassette 48)
- CCNY Memorial Description: Recording of Dedication of memorial for 13 CCNY alumni members of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade killed in action in the Spanish Civil War., Apr 13, 1980 (Cassette 46A-B)
- Edigio Clemente Description: Editor of La Parole, and secretary of Italian Socialist Federation, 1930s., May 11, 1981 (Cd ohaloh020020p1 / ohaloh020020p2, Cd Access OH-02-020, Cassette 50)
- Lucy Ann Cloud Description: Industrial Workers of the World, Centralia, Wash. reference to Elmer Smith, IWW attorney., Aug 25, 1972 (Item Transcript only)
- Charles Coe, Jan 1, 1992 (Cassette 315A-B)
  No access cassettes available / masters only
- Nat Cohen, 11/5/1979 (Cassette 392)
- Rose Cohen Description: Jefferson School of Social Science., Apr 12, 1976 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Joseph & Ruth Cohen Description: On "Carlo" (Jesse Cohen), cartoonist of the Workers Party, 1940s., Jun 9, 1983 (Cassette 51A-B)
- Julia Conroy, May 14, 1980 (Cd ohaloh020194p1 / ohaloh020194p2, Cassette 53)
- Olga Corey; Description: Experiences of Louis Fraina/Lewis Corey's daughter; reaction to the movie Reds; reminiscences of father at Antioch College, 1940s; her own union activities., Jan 18, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020195p1 / ohaloh020195p2, Cassette 54)
- Carlos Cortez Description: Workers of the World and San Diego Free Speech Fight, anarchism and IWW., Jul 25, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020196b1p1 / ohaloh020196b1p2, Cd ohaloh020197b1p3 / ohaloh020197b1p4, Cassette 55)
  Transcript available, Box 1 and index available
- Malcolm Cowley Description: Left in the Depression; League of Professional Groups, "Culture and the Crisis," 1932; the proletarian novel; John Reed Clubs; Popular Front; Spanish Civil War; reflections., Jan 19, 1981 (Cassette 56, Cd ohaloh020087p1 / ohaloh020087p2, Cd Access OH-02-91 / OH-02-092)
- Carl Cowl, March 13, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020198p1 / ohaloh020198p2, Cassette 57)
- Roy Curtis, Nov. 4, 1984 (Cassette 308A-B)
  No access cassettes / Masters only
- Joseph Cvetas Description: SNPJ (Slovenian Benefit Society); fraternalism., Oct 23, 1982 (Cd ohaloh020199p1 / ohaloh020199p2, Cassette 58)
- James Cannon, n.d. (Cassette n/a, Cd ohaloh020028p1 / ohaloh020028p2, Cd Access 29)
- Sam Darcy Description:Communist activities; Browderism; 1920s. [See also Sam Darcy Papers, Tamiment Library]., 1981 (Cassette 59, Cd ohaloh020021b1p1 / ohaloh020021b1p2, Cd ohaloh020022b1p3, Cd Access OH-02-021 / OH-02-022 / OH-02-023)
- Sam Darcy, Nov. 3, 1994 (Cassette 342)
- Sam Darcy, Nov. 4, 1994 (Cassette 343A-B)
- Saul Davidson Description: "United Front;" Yiddish activist and preservation., Mar 16, 1983 (Cd ohaloh020200p1 / ohaloh020200p2, Cassette 60)
- Sam Davis Description: Role of Jewish Left; Yiddishe Kultur Farband choir; Morgen Freiheit; Communists in YKUF/Jewish Currents circle; 1920s., Nov 15, 1980 (Cd ohaloh020201b1p1 / ohaloh020201b1p2, Cd ohaloh020202b1p3, Cassette 61)
- Zoltan Deak Description: Hungarian-American radical press, Uj Elore and Hungarian Word, 1920s- 1980s., Feb 17, 1983 (Cassette 62, Cd Access OH-02-024, Cd ohaloh020023p1 / ohaloh020023p2)
- Jeannette Dean Description: Union activities; radicalism., Apr 14, 1979 (Cassette 63)
- Solon De Leon Description: Socialist Party and reformism; Solon's break with Daniel DeLeon; IWW; Industrial Union League and Socialist Labor Party, c. 1900s-1930s., Dec 16, 1972 (Cassette 65A-C)
- Albina Delfino Description: Italian-American women and the Communist Party, Needle Trades Industrial Union, National Textile Workers Union; 1930s-40s., Jan 8, 1981 (Cd ohaloh0200092b1p1 / ohaloh0200092b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200093b1p3 / ohaloh0200093b1p4, Cassette 66)